Carl Oglesby Papers, 1942-2005
Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3: Yankee and Cowboy War, 1970-2002
  - Typescript: assorted, 1973, undated (Box 20)
  - Typescript: chapter 6, "Watergate", circa 1988-1990 (Box 20)
  - Typescript: chapter 7, "Carter: The Scalawag President and the Hostage Crisis", circa 1975-1977 (Box 20)
  - Typescript: chapter 10, "Bush: One-Man Yankee-Cowboy Coalition", 1987-1989 (Box 20)
  - Typescript: chapter 11, "Beyond the Frontier", 1989-1990 (Box 20)
  - Typescript: Yankee-Cowboy War history, circa 1988-1990 (Box 20)
  - Writing fragments, undated (Box 20)
  - Writing fragments: Northgate, circa 1981-1986 (Box 20)
  - Writing fragments: Northgate, circa 1981-1986 (Box 21)
  - Writing fragments: Reagan administration, 1974-1981 (Box 21)
- Series 4: Gehlen Organization, 1945-2005
  - "Anti-Communism and the U.S.: History and Consequences, an International Conference", 1988 (Box 21)
  - "Anti-Communism and the U.S.: History and Consequences, an International Conference," notes, 1988 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Agoston, Blunder! How the U.S. Gave Away Nazi Supersecrets to Russia, undated (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: assorted, various dates (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Brussell, Mac, "The Nazi Connection to the John F. Kennedy Assassination", 1983 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Cannon, Martin, "Part One: The Witnesses", undated (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Carrington, Ellsworth T., 1980-1981, 1991 (Box 21)
    Includes a letter to Oglesby.
  - Articles and books: Colvin, Ian, "The Secret Front", 1954 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Edwards, Bob and Dunne, Kenneth, "A Study of a Master Spy (Allen Dulles)", circa 1961 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Hermann, Kai. "Klaus Barbie: A Killer's Career", 1986 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Infield, Glenn B., "Skerzeny: Hitler's Commando", 1981 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Jensen, Joan M., "The Price of Vigilance:, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Judge, John, "Good Americans", undated (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: King, Dennis, 1981-1984 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Lee, Martin, "Der Spiegal", 1990-1991 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Lee, Martin A., "Hitler's Offspring", 1993 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Light, Robert E. and Marzani, Carl, "Cuba vs. the C.I.A.", 1961 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Manning, Paul, "Wharton -- Nazi in Exile", undated (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Martin, James Stewart, "All Honorable Men", 1950 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Miller, Arthur, "Uneasy About the Germans", 1990 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Oglesby, Carl, "The Secret Treaty of Fort Hunt", 1990 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Pearson, David, "K.A.L. 077: What the U.S. Knew and When We Knew It", 1984 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Prevailing Winds Research, "Tied Up in Nazis", undated (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Riess, Curt, "The Nazis Go Underground", 1944 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Rostow, Eugene V., "Peace in the Balance: the Future of American Foreign Policy", 1972 (Box 21)
  - Articles and books: Scott, Peter Dale, "How Allen Dulles and the SS Preserved Each Other", 1986 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Sereny, Gitta, "Children of the Rich", 1990 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Skolnick, Sherman H., "Princess Diana: Crushed Between East and West", 1996 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Speer, Albert, "Infiltration: How Heinrich Himmler Schemed to Build an SS Industrial Empire", 1981 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Taylor, Telford, "Chilly Winds", circa 1984 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Van Renterghem, Tony, 1985-1987 (Box 22)
  - Articles and books: Wiesenthal, Simon, "The Wanderers Among Us", 1967 (Box 22)
  - Bibliographies, circa 1990, undated (Box 22)
  - Book materials: note cards, undated (Box 22)
  - Book materials: note cards, undated (Box 23)
  - Book materials: note cards, undated (Box 23)
  - Book notes, various dates (Box 23)
  - Book reviews, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Brochures and announcements, circa 1985-1991 (Box 23)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1988 (Box 23)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1988 (Box 23)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1989 (Box 23)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1989 (Box 23)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1989 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1989 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1990 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1990 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1990 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1991 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1992 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1992 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1993 (Box 24)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1993 (Box 25)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1994-1995 (Box 25)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1996 (Box 25)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 1997-1998 (Box 25)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, 2000-2003 (Box 25)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, undated (Box 25)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": court documents, undated (Box 26)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": FOIA requests, undated (Box 26)
  - "Carl Oglesby v. Department of the Army": notes, undated (Box 26)
  - Charts: Gehlen Organization, undated (Box 26)
  - Charts: Nazi War Crimes Disclosure Act, 2002
  - Catalogs, 1987-2003 (Box 26)
  - Chronology: Gehlen, circa 1985 (Box 26)
  - Chronology: Gehlen, undated (Box 26)
  - Chronology: Gehlen, undated (Box 26)
  - Chronology: "Nazification of U.S. Intelligence", circa 1984 (Box 26)
  - Congressional report: "GAO Report on Nazi War Criminals in the United States", 1985 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, 1984-2003 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Department of the Army, 1997 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Freedom of Information Act, 1985-1987 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Freedom of Information Act, 1985-1987 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Freedom of Information Act, 1999-2001 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Gallen, Richard, 1992 (Box 27)
    Includes book proposal.
  - Correspondence; Institute for Continuing Denazification, 1989-1996 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Klimke, Martin, 2005 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Lesar, James, 1987-1990 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Lesar, James, 1991-1997 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Meredith, Scott, 1985 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Rockefeller, Abby and Lee, 1987-2003 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence: Woods, Phil, 2003 (Box 27)
  - Documents: Association of Former Intelligence Officers, membership directory, 1989 (Box 28)
  - Documents: Bellant, Russ, "Old Nazis, the New Right and the Reagan Administration", 1988 (Box 28)
  - Documents: "Elkhorn Document," Davis, William R., undated (Box 28)
    Includes only portions of copied document.
  - Documents: "Klaus Barbie and the United States Government, "Ryan, Allan A., 1983; p. 1-134 (Box 28)
  - Documents: "Klaus Barbie and the United States Government, "Ryan, Allan A., 1983 (Box 28)
  - Documents: "History of the Counter Intelligence Corps: Chronology", 1959; v. 2 (Box 28)
  - Documents: "History of the Counter Intelligence Corps: Chronology", 1959; v. 2 (Box 28)
  - Documents: "Robert Jan Verbelen and the United States Governmnet", 1988 (Box 28)
  - Drafts: Institute for Continuing Denazification, 1986 (Box 28)
  - Intelligence documents: Dietrich, Heinz, circa 1952-1957 (Box 28)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1941-1961 (Box 28)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1941-1961 (Box 29)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1945-1946 (Box 29)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1945-1947 (Box 29)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1945-1947 (Box 29)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1945-1947 (Box 29)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1946 (Box 29)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1946 (Box 29)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1945-1946 (Box 29)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1945-1946 (Box 30)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946 (Box 30)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946 (Box 30)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946 (Box 30)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946 (Box 30)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946 (Box 30)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946 (Box 31)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946-1948 (Box 31)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946-1948 (Box 31)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946-1954 (Box 31)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946-1954 (Box 31)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946-1955 (Box 31)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946-1955 (Box 31)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1946-1966 (Box 32)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1950-1962 (Box 32)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1950-1962 (Box 32)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1951-1953 (Box 32)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1951-1953 (Box 32)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1953-1956 (Box 32)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1953-1956 (Box 32)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1953-1956 (Box 33)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1954 (Box 33)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1954 (Box 33)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1954-1956 (Box 33)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, circa 1954-1956 (Box 33)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1956-1958 (Box 33)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1958-1959 (Box 33)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1956-1958 (Box 34)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1956-1958 (Box 34)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1959 (Box 34)
  - Intelligence documents: Gehlen, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
  - Intelligence documents: National Security Agency, 1990 (Box 34)
  - Intelligence documents: Ryan Report, 1945 (Box 34)
  - Intelligence documents: Werewolf, 1945 (Box 35)
  - Intelligence documents: Werewolf Organization, circa 1945-1948 (Box 35)
  - Intelligence documents: Werewolf Organization, circa 1945-1948 (Box 35)
  - Intelligence documents: Werewolf Organization, circa 1945-1948 (Box 35)
  - Intelligence documents: Werewolf Organization, circa 1945-1948 (Box 35)
  - Intelligence documents: Werewolf Organization, circa 1945-1948 (Box 35)
  - Intelligence documents: Werewolf Organization, circa 1945-1948 (Box 35)
  - Intelligence documents: Werewolf Organization, circa 1945-1948 (Box 36)
  - Lecture materials, 1984, undated (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: "Mengle and Dulles: the SS-OSS Connection, Transnationalism and the Cold War," Scott, Peter Dale, circa 1985 (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: "J. Edgar Hoover: the Father of the Cold War," Kiel, Andrew R.P, undated; p. 1-109 (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: "J. Edgar Hoover: the Father of the Cold War," Kiel, Andrew R., undated; p. 130-256 (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: "J. Edgar Hoover: the Father of the Cold War," Kiel, Andrew R., undated; p. 257-367 (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: "J. Edgar Hoover: the Father of the Cold War," Kiel, Andrew R., undated; p. 369-475 (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: Oglesby, Carl, "The Nazification of U.S. Intelligence", undated (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: Oglesby, Carl, "Reinhard Gehlen and the Secret Tragedy of Fort Hunt", undated (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: Oglesby, Carl, "The Secret Deal of Fort Hunt", 1985 (Box 36)
  - Manuscript: Oglesby, Carl, "The Secret Deal of Fort Hunt", 1990 (Box 37)
  - Manuscript: Oglesby, Carl, untitled, undated (Box 37)
  - Manuscript: Oglesby, Carl, untitled, undated (Box 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1985 (Box 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1986 (Box 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1987 (Box 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1988 (Box 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1989 (Box 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1990 (Box 37)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1991-1995 (Box 38)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 38)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2000-2005, undated (Box 38)
  - Newspaper clippings: German, circa 1956 (Box 38)
  - Newspaper clippings: Mengle, Joseph, 1985 (Box 38)
  - Newspaper clippings: Nazi war criminals in the U.S., 1977-1987 (Box 38)
  - Notes, various dates (Box 38)
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 38)
    Chapter 1, "1945: A Reintroduction."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 39)
    Chapter 2, "Twilight of the OSS."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 39)
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 39)
    Chapter 3, "Odessa."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 39)
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 39)
    Chapter 4, "Secret Wars."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 39)
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 39)
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 40)
    Chapter 5, "Separate Peace."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 40)
    Chapter 6, "Installation, Gehlen Organization."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 40)
    Chapter 7, "Barbie-Gehlen Link."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 40)
    Chapter 7, "Barbie-Gehlen Organization."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 40)
    Chapter 8, "Gehlen Falls."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 40)
    Chapter 9, "Nazism Reprieved."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 40)
    Chapter 10, "Consequences of the Nazi Peace."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
    Appendix A, "Historical Profile of U.S. Secret Intelligence."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
    Appendix B, "The Nazification: A Chronology."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
    Appendix C, "The Papal Assassination Attempt: A Case Study of the Odessa Legacy."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
    Appendix D, "On Sources and Documentation."
  - A Nazi Peace, 1984-1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
    Preface, "In Defense of Paranoia."
  - A Nazi Peace: outline, undated; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
  - A Nazi Peace: proposal, 1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
  - "Odessa Rising": book materials, undated; Oglesby, Carl (Box 41)
  - Photographs: Gehlen, undated (Box 41)
  - Printed materials, various dates (Box 41)
  - Printed materials: Covert Action Information Bulletin (Box 42)
  - Printed materials: Covert Action Information Bulletin, 1980 Dec-1983; nos. 11-17 (Box 42)
  - Printed materials: Covert Action Information Bulletin, 1983-1985; nos. 18-23 (Box 42)
  - Printed materials: Covert Action Information Bulletin, 1984-1987; nos. 24-27 (Box 42)
  - Printed materials: Covert Action Information Bulletin, 1988-1992; nos. 29-33, 42 (Box 42)
  - Printed materials: Counter-Spy, 1971; v. 1, nos. 1-2 (Box 42)
  - Printed materials: "Federal Register: Part IV, The President", 1982 (Box 42)
  - Printed materials: Liberty, 1989 (Box 42)
    Vol. 3, no. 1.
  - Printed materials: Lobster, undated (Box 43)
  - Printed materials: Prevailing Winds, 2000 (Box 43)
    No. 6.
  - Printed materials: Special Intelligence Report, undated (Box 43)
    No. 3.
  - Printed materials: T op Secret: International News and Analyses, 1990 (Box 43)
  - Project Nazi File: correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 43)
  - Project Nazi File: correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 43)
  - Project Nazi File: correspondence, 1990-1991, undated (Box 43)
  - Project Nazi File: correspondence with staff associates, 1990 (Box 43)
  - Project Nazi File: drafts, 1987 (Box 43)
  - Project Nazi File: drafts, 1987-1988 (Box 43)
  - Project Nazi File: notes 1987 (Box 43)
  - Project Nazi File: proposal, 2005 (Box 43)
  - Proposal: "The Secret Treaty of fort Hunt", 1992 (Box 44)
  - Script: "Superspy", circa 1985 (Box 44)
  - Speech: Oglesby, Carl, "The Secret Treaty of Fort Hunt, 1945", 1985 (Box 44)
  - Terrel, Jack: court documents, 1988 (Box 44)
  - Terrell, Jack: notes and news clippings, 1988-1997 (Box 44)
  - Transcript: Oglesby, Carl, "The Nazi Connection", 1989 (Box 44)
  - Writing fragments (Box 44)
- Series 5: Other Writings and Research, 1959-2004
  - Subseries 1: Ravens on the Wing, 1959-2003
    - Correspondence, 1977-1996 (Box 44)
    - Draft, undated (Box 44)
    - Draft, undated (Box 44)
      Chapters 1, 4.
    - Draft, undated (Box 44)
      Chapters 5-7.
    - Draft, undated (Box 44)
      Chapters 8-14.
    - Draft, undated (Box 45)
      Chapters 15-18.
    - Draft, undated (Box 45)
      Chapters 20-25.
    - Draft, undated (Box 45)
      Chapter 9, multiple versions.
    - Draft, undated (Box 45)
      Chapter 10, multiple versions.
    - Draft, undated (Box 45)
      Chapter 11, multiple versions.
    - Draft, undated (Box 45)
      Chapter 12, multiple versions.
    - Notes, 1994-1995 (Box 45)
    - Research materials, 1973-2003 (Box 45)
    - Research materials, 1973-2003 (Box 46)
    - Research materials, 1973-2003 (Box 46)
    - Research materials: chapter 9, 1968-1986 (Box 46)
    - Research materials: chapter 10, 1986-1993 (Box 46)
    - Research materials: chapter 10, 1986-1993 (Box 46)
    - Research materials: chapter 11, circa 1980-1999 (Box 46)
    - Research materials: chapter 11, 1980-1999 (Box 46)
    - Research materials: chapter 12, circa 1968 (Box 47)
      Contains photographs and clippings, of Oglesby's trip to Cuba.
    - Research materials: chapter 12, circa 1968-1993 (Box 47)
    - Research materials: Russel Tribunal, 1959-1974 (Box 47)
    - Research materials: SDS, circa 1973-1977 (Box 47)
    - Writing fragments, undated (Box 47)
    - Writing fragments, undated (Box 47)
    - Writing fragments: chapter 10, 1970-1996 (Box 48)
  - Subseries 2: Miscellaneous Writings and Research, 1961-2002
    - Academic papers, circa 1961-1962 (Box 48)
    - Articles, 1964-1965 (Box 48)
    - Articles, 1966-1967 (Box 48)
    - Articles, 1968-1969 (Box 48)
    - Articles, 1970-1972 (Box 48)
    - Articles, 1973 (Box 48)
    - Articles, 1974-1978 (Box 48)
    - Articles, 1979-1980 (Box 49)
    - Articles, 1981-1988 (Box 49)
    - Articles, 1990-2000 (Box 49)
    - Articles: Boston Phoenix, 1972 (Box 49)
    - Articles: Boston Phoenix, 1973 (Box 49)
    - Articles: FBI and CIA, 1978-1985 (Box 49)
    - Articles: "Getting Back to Watergate at last", 1981 (Box 49)
    - Articles: "The Vietnam War: World Revolution and American Containment", 1965 (Box 49)
      SDS position paper on Vietnam.
    - "Mailer's Bad Company", 1991; Badrich, Steve (Box 49)
      Review of Norman Mailer's Harlot's Ghost.
    - Bibliography, 1964-1992 (Box 49)
    - Civil/Military Alliance in Emergency Management, 1982 (Box 49)
    - Correspondence, 1975-2002 (Box 49)
    - Correspondence: Chomsky, Noam, 1981 (Box 49)
      Includes drafts, articles by Oglesby about Chomsky.
    - Draft, "Double Agent: What Deep Throat Didn't Know About Watergate", 1984 (Box 50)
    - Draft, "In Defense of Paranoia", 1974 (Box 50)
    - Draft, "One Nation, Divisible", 1981-1982 (Box 50)
    - Draft, "Sympathy for the Devil", undated (Box 50)
    - Manuscript manuals: "Nick's Way", circa 1980-1989 (Box 50)
    - Editorial, draft, 1981; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - Editorial, The Nation, 1980 Feb 16; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - "Fingerprints on Agca's Gun are Agca's," drafts, 1984; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - "It Can Happen Again", 1998; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
      Review of Martin Lee's The Beast Reawakens.
    - "Life at the End of the Road: Jungians at the Apocalypse", 1983 Sept; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - "My Dinner with Andrey: A True Story of the Cold War", 1983 Nov; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - "New German Philosopher! New German Philosopher! What Does This Man Mean to Say?", 1970; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - "Open Letter to McCarthy Supporters", 1968; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - "P-2 Connection: Was Agca Used by Italian Fascists?", 1985; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
      Co-written by Jerry Miller.
    - Peacemaker, 1963; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - Season of the Beast, 1956; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - "Trapped in a System", undated; Oglesby, Carl (Box 50)
    - "World Before Watergate", 1978 May; Oglesby, Carl (Box 51)
    - Poetry fragments: "Tobie's Book", circa 1992-1996 (Box 51)
    - Poetry fragments: "Verse Vice", circa 1983-1998 (Box 51)
    - Research materials: Agca, Mehmet Ali, 1982-1985 (Box 51)
    - Research materials: Agca, Mehmet Ali, 1985 (Box 51)
    - Research materials: Bush, George, 1988-1990 (Box 51)
    - Research materials: general, 1950-2004 (Box 51)
    - Research materials: North, Oliver, 1986-1990 (Box 51)
    - Research materials: Sunbelt, 1980-1981 (Box 51)
    - Research materials: Sunbelt, circa 1981 (Box 52)
    - "The Fifth Horseman of the Apocalypse: Civil Security During and After the Unthinkable", 1983; Salcedo, Frank S. (Box 52)
    - World Bank Report, 1970 (Box 52)
    - Writing fragments and other materials: "Kingdoms of Twilight", circa 1981 (Box 52)
  - Subseries 3: Religion, 1971-2004
    - Draft" "Art at the Apocalypse", 1982 (Box 52)
    - Draft" "Art at the Apocalypse", 1982 (Box 52)
    - Draft" "Art at the Apocalypse", 1982 (Box 52)
    - Draft: "Rescuing Jesus From the Cross", 1983 (Box 52)
    - Manuscript: "The Sermons of Judas", circa 1971 (Box 52)
    - Manuscript: "The Sermons of Judas", circa 1971 (Box 52)
    - Religious materials, 1995-2004 (Box 53)
    - Research materials: "The Sermons of Judas", 1982-2003 (Box 53)
- Series 6: Personal, 1942-2003
  - Announcements and invitations, 1956-2001 (Box 53)
  - Articles: Clinton, Hillary, 1994 (Box 53)
  - Biographical material: Oglesby, Carl, 1978 (Box 53)
  - Book excerpt" "Bill of Rights Journal", 1995 (Box 53)
  - Book reviews: "Bob Villa's Dream House", 1990-1991 (Box 53)
  - Brochures: "When Students Made History", circa 1980 (Box 53)
  - Calendar, 1994 (Box 53)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS: Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box 53)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS): drafts, "Religion and Conflict", 1982-1992 (Box 53)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS): Johnston, Doug, writings, 1992-1999 (Box 54)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS): Luttwak, Edward N., writings, 1989 (Box 54)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS): meeting notes and status reports, 1987-1989 (Box 54)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS): notes and newspaper clippings, 1988 (Box 54)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS): paper proposals, "Religion and Conflict", 1988 (Box 54)
  - Class reunion, 1997-2001 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence, 1993-2001 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence: Citizens' Review Commission on the FBI, 1979 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence: Diabacco, Aron and Art, 1973-2003 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence: Dohrn, Bernadine, 1989 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence: Filmore, Laura, 1992-1993 (Box 54)
  - Correspondence: Flanagan, Darrell, 2001-2005 (Box 54)
    Includes materials on various conspiracy theories.
  - Correspondence: Mailer, Norman, 1977-1992 (Box 55)
  - Correspondence: Miller, Robert Carl, 1991 (Box 55)
    Includes articles on conspiracy theories.
  - Correspondence: Naimen, Arthur, 1992-1993 (Box 55)
    From Odonian Press.
  - Correspondence: Oglesby, Caleb, 1986-1994 (Box 55)
  - Correspondence: Oglesby, Terry and Eddie, circa 1994 (Box 55)
  - Correspondence: papers of Carl Oglesby, 1974-1999 (Box 55)
    Concerning the placement of Oglesby's papers.